Finding Aid for The Frick Collection Central Files, 1932-1936 TFC.0400.010
The Frick Collection/Frick Art Reference Library Archives
- Central Files, 1936
  - Mimeographing, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 21)
    Contains copy of Preliminary Handbook of The Frick Collection, for staff use only. Notes the materials of stonework, floors, sculpture, plants, furniture, art and decorative objects in each room.
  - Morgan, Junius S. [Trustees], 1936 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Museum Management - Data re Other Museums, 1935-1936 (Box 39, Folder 23)
    Contains information from the Boston Museum of Fine Arts, the Brooklyn Museum, the Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum, and the Metropolitan Museum of Art regarding holidays, hours, salaries, vacations, and pension plans.
  - Museum Management - Industrial Relations Counselors, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 24)
    Contains reports regarding personnel policies (salary, disability benefits, group life insurance, personnel records, hiring procedures) and a Contributory Pension System.
  - Museum Management - Maintenance, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 25)
    Includes handbook:Duties of Engineers' Department.
  - Museum Management - Office Procedure, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 26)
    Contains memo: "Note on Changes Required to Give Frick Collection Conventional Museum Setting."
  - Museum Management - Samples of Announcements, etc., 1936 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - M - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 28)
    Magnanti, Angelo
    [The] Marley Company, Inc.
    Mather, Frank Jewett, Jr.
    McDougall & Potter Co.
    Morison, C. T. & Company, Inc.
    Moths
    Mullligan, Thomas F.
    Mount Vernon - Contains 1936 booklet.
  - New York Art Calendar, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - N - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - Organ, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 31)
  - Organ Music, 1935-1936 (Box 39, Folder 32)
  - Organ Sound Transmission, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 33)
  - Organists, 1935-1936 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Organization Chart, 1936 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    Lists Board of Trustees, Executive, Finance and Acquisitions Committee Members, and Collection staff. Oversize charts stored in Box B.
  - Osborn, Frederick H. [Trustee], 1936 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Overholt, Karl F., 1936 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Pay Roll [RESTRICTED FILE], 1936 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Pay Roll - Overtime [3 folders] [RESTRICTED FILE], 1936 (Box 40, Folder 6-8)
  - Photographic Department, 1936 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, 1935-1936 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Photographs - Bills, 1936 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Photographers, 1935-1936 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    Material filed by photographer name; general material filed in back.
    Amemya, Yosei
    Brennasser, Eugene
    Costain, Harold
    Cotis, Mr.
    Donnelley, R. R.
    French, Arthur
    Gottscho, Samuel H.
    Hagelstein Bros.
    Juley, Peter A. Sons.
    Loeb, S. S.
    Morton, Alexander
    Pach, Alfred, Jr.
    Schnall Photography
    Seidman Photo Service
  - Photographers - Lyons, Joseph, 1936 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    Photographer hired by The Frick Collection from the Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum, with the encouragement of director Morris Carter. Includes correspondence with Morris Carter.
  - Photographic Equipment, 1936 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Pittsburgh, University of - Department of Fine Arts, 1936 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Planting - Committee, Executive, 1936 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    Re the Fifth Avenue Garden.
  - Planting - Innocenti and Webel [landscape architects], 1936 (Box 40, Folder 17)
    Umberto Innocenti - Richard K. Webel.
  - Planting - Lewis and Valentine [nursery], 1936 (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Planting - Miscellaneous, 1936-1937 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    Re Garden Court and Fifth Avenue Garden.
  - Planting - Olmstead Brothers [landscape architects], 1936 (Box 40, Folder 20)
    Re monthly visits to inspect and advise on Garden Court plants.
  - Planting - Roehrs, Julius [nursery], 1936 (Box 40, Folder 21)
    Re Garden Court plants.
  - Pope, John Russell [architect], 1936 (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Pope, John Russell [architect] - Bills, Correspondence re, 1936 (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Pope, John Russell [architect] - Extras for Which Architects Were Responsible, 1935-1936 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Pope, John Russell [architect] - Minutes of Weekly Conferences, 1936 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    Last weekly meeting held on January 16, 1936.
  - Pope, John Russell [architect] - Record Drawings, 1935-1936 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Post Cards - Meriden Gravure Company, 1935-1936 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    Printers of The Frick Collection post cards. Contains list of pictures selected for post cards, correspondence, and company brochures.
  - Post Cards - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    Contains samples and correspondence from Bernard Metal Lithotex.
  - Post Cards - Stern, Edward & Company [2 folders], 1936 (Box 41, Folder 6-7)
    Printers of The Frick Collection post cards using Aquatone process. Contains samples of rejected cards.
  - Printing [2 folders], 1936-1937 (Box 41, Folder 8-9)
    Re items printed. Includes some samples of Collection forms and tickets.
  - Printing - Forms, 1936 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Projection Apparatus - Zeiss, Carl, Inc. [2 folders], 1936 (Box 41, Folder 11-12)
  - Projection Equipment, 1936 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Publicity - Committee, 1936 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Publicity - Lee and Ross, 1936 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    Ivy Lee and T.J. Ross.
  - Publicity - Miscellaneous, 1935-1936 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    Includes correspondence, two clippings, and a copy of The Decorators Digest(February 1936) with an article on The Frick Collection. Also contains December 21, 1936 memo: "Memorandum for a News Report on the First Year of The Frick Collection" that contains a summary re changes in attendance, hours, circulation, ticketing, photographic department, lectures and groups, music and acquisitions.
  - P - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    Paper [Japan Paper Company]
    Passes
    Plaza Service Company, Inc.
    Pipes
    Purchasing Dept.
  - Q - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    Quotations - Contains instructions for copying a quotation.
  - Remington Rand Inc., 1935-1936 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Repairs - Building - Income Account, 1935-1936 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Reports of Director to Executive Committee, 1936 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Reports of Director to Trustees, 1936 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    Two summary reports concern attendance, ticket office, hours, personnel, equipment, rehanging of the works of art, summer cleaning, relighting, exterior repairs, water meters, air conditioning, Photographic Department, record cards, Lecture Room, lectures, concerts, the Garden Court, Fifth Avenue terraces, illumination of the Fragonard and Boucher panels, condition of the paintings, Piero della Francesca accession, fire insurance, construction account, and budget statement.
  - Reproductions - Miscellaneous, 1935-1936 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Requests for Admission [3 folders], 1936 (Box 42, Folder 9-11)
  - Requests for Admission - Groups [2 folders], 1935-1937 (Box 42, Folder 12-13)
  - Requests for Catalogue [2 folders], 1936 (Box 42, Folder 14-15)
  - Requests for Descriptive Material, 1936 (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Requests for Financial Aid, 1936 (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Requests for Information re Building, 1936 (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - Requests - Miscellaneous, 1935-1936 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Requests for Permission to Reproduce Pictures, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    Includes two letters from author David K. E. Bruce.
  - Requests for Photographs, 1935-1936 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Requests for Photographs - Construction, 1935-1936 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Requests for Post Cards, 1935-1936 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Requests for Slides, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Resignation, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    Re withdrawal of Frederick Mortimer Clapp's resignation after clarification of the Director's responsibilities and powers by the Board of Trustees.
  - Rockefeller, John D., Jr. [Trustee], 1936 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Rooms, Description of, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    Contains preliminary Handbook of The Frick Collection. Also contains of schedule of rooms and space numbers for both The Frick Collection and the Frick Art Reference Library.
  - R - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    Rijksmuseum
    Rules and Regulations - The Frick Collection
    Richter, Miss
    Riker & Company, Inc. - Re real estate.
    Rooms - Re schedule of room numbers for The Frick Collection.
  - Seating, 1935-1936 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    Re chairs for the Lecture Room from the American Seating Company. Includes leather samples.
  - Services for Sale, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Signs, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    Re text for signs for lectures, organ recitals, and Collection hours.
  - Skylights, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    Contains correspondence with G. Drouve Company re leakage and cracks.
  - Slides, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    Contains correspondence re slides made for lectures.
  - Statements - Budget, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Statements - Construction - Connected Items, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Statements - Construction Account, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Statements - Construction Account - U.S. Trust Company, 1936-1937 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Statements - Maintenance and Operating Account, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Statements - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Steam Cleaning, 1935-1936 (Box 43, Folder 22)
    Re cleaning of exterior stone work by Remark Building Service Co., Inc.
  - Stonework - Pointing and Preservation, 1934-1936 (Box 43, Folder 23)
    Re chemical treatment and repointing of joints for all exterior stonework (Collection and Library buildings).
  - Storeroom, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Syska & Hennessy [consulting engineers], 1936 (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - Syska & Hennessy [consulting engineers] - Bills, 1935-1936 (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Syska & Hennessy [consulting engineers] - Record Drawings, 1934-1937 (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - S - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 28)
    Safety deposit boxes
    Salvage - Includes pencil drawing on tracing paper of porte-cochere and other stonework details that went to Helen Clay Frick. Oversize drawings on tracing paper stored in flat files. Photograph transferred to The Frick Collection - Photographs; folder contains photocopy of photograph.
    Social Security
    Sound deadening
    Standards (for velvet ropes)
    Steuben Glass Inc.
    Student Tickets
  - Tax Exemption - Income, 1936 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Tax Exemption - Property, 1936 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Tax Exemption - Sales, 1936-1937 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Tax - Sales, Catalogues and Post Cards, 1935-1937 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Taxes, Income, 1936-1937 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Telephone System, 1936 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Ticket Office, 1936 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    Contains sample tickets, pencil drawing on tracing paper of ticket sign, and chart of types of ticket requests.
  - Trustees' Meetings - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Trustees - Minutes of Meetings [RESTRICTED FILE], 1936 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Trustees - Minutes of Meetings, Extracts from [RESTRICTED FILE], 1931-1936 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Trustees - Officers, Committees, 1932-1936 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Turnstiles, 1936 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    Oversize drawing on tracing paper stored in Box B.
  - T - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    Telephone Directory
  - United States Trust Company, 1936 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - U - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    United States Post Office
  - Vacations, 1936 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Ventilation of Boiler and Compressor Rooms, 1936 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Visitors, 1936 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - V - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 44, Folder 19)
    Vouchers
  - Western Union, 1936 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Wine Removal from Building, 1936 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Window Cleaning, 1935-1936 (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - W - Miscellaneous, 1935 (Box 44, Folder 23)
    Weather
    Whippo, Harold
    Worcester Art Museum
  - X-Y-Z - Miscellaneous, 1935 (Box 44, Folder 24)
    Zolnay, Charles, Jr.